Inventory of the Leslie H. Dingyan Chen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leslie H. Dingyan Chen papers
1912-2007
2009C21
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Biographical data, personal documents, notes, printed matter, photographs, and videocassette relating to the Chinese politician Chen Jiongming (father of Leslie Chen) and the Chen family. Includes research material used by Leslie Chen in his book Chen Jiongming and the Federalist Movement: Regional Leadership and Nation Building in Early Republican China (Ann Arbor, 1999).
Chen, Leslie H. Dingyan
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Chinese-American engineer and historian.
Scope and Content of Collection
Biographical data, personal documents, notes, printed matter, photographs, and videocassette relating to the Chinese politician Chen Jiongming (father of Leslie Chen) and the Chen family. Includes research material used by Leslie Chen in his book Chen Jiongming and the Federalist Movement: Regional Leadership and Nation Building in Early Republican China (Ann Arbor, 1999).
Chen, Jiongming, 1878-1933.; China--History--1912-1928.; Chinese--United States.
- Chen Jiongming File, 1912-1998
  Scope and Contents note
  Presumably much of this file was source material for the book Chen Jiongming and the Federalist Movement: Regional Leadership and Nation Building in Early Republican China.
  - Historical photograph files, 1912-1935 (Box-folder 1 :1-2)
  - Biographical sketch, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Family tree, 1998 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1998 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Published articles about Chen Jiongming, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Chen Dingyan File, 1933-2006
  - Family photographs, 1933-2000 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Portraits, undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Graduation certificates and copies, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Mechanical engineer awards, 1976-2004 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Research and publications in mechanical engineering, 1961-1986 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Chen Jiongming and the Federalist Movement
    - Author and bibliographic information, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Reference materials, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Sun Yatsun: Frustrated Patriot, 1976
    - Glossary of names, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Book promotion materials, 1999 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Gao Zonglu, Chen Dingyan book launch press conference videocassette and CD, 1997 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Memorial, 2006 (Box-folder 1: 18)
- Chen Dingye File, 1991
  - Photographs taken in China and France, 1991 (Box-folder 1: 19)